本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:东吾 king  翻译:念白白 poopy   校对:木落 时间轴:wcaster
蟲奉行所はどこだ
Where's the Insect Magistrate's Office?
ああ　兄さん迷子かい
Are you lost?
しかしあんた　ずいぶん匂うね
Anyway, you really stink...
ああ　蟲奉行所か
So, the Magistrate's, right?
確かこの先をまがって　まっすぐ行ったとこ
Just around that corner, then go straight.
Wait, no...
じゃなくて
Was it this way?
こっちだったかな
知らないなら　もう用はない
If you don't know, I don't need you anymore.
Insect!? Man!?
A Mysterious Enemy Attacks!
【蟲？人？謎の敵　襲来】
Why are you always causing problems?
どうしていつもいつも問題を起こす
The City Patrol really is a bunch
of low-class incompetents.
やはり貴様ら市中組は下賤で無能の集まりだな
I am very sorry...
申し訳ありません
貴様の謝罪など　求めておらぬわ
I don't need your apologies!
I need to know why the entire
City Patrol is on vacation!
なぜ市中組の同心全員が休暇を取っておるのかと聞いている
いや　その　みんながどうしてもっと
Well, you see...
Everyone insisted...
いつ帰ってくるのだ
When will they return?
ええと
A-Ah...
どこに行った
Where did they go?
その
Well...
月島だけ休むなんて　ずるいわよ
It isn't fair that only Tsukishima gets a vacation.
You can handle things yourself, Kotori-chan.
小鳥ちゃんがいれば　なんとかなるだろう
Have fun.
あとはよろしくな
I'll be off, as well...
僕も休む
えー　ちょっとみんな
Wait, everyone!
職場放棄
You're abandoning your jobs!
Mugai-kun's gone, too.
無涯君もいなくなっちゃったし
Everyone, I'm cutting your salary.
みんな　絶対給料を減らすからね
Matsunohara!
松ノ原
ああ　でも仁兵衛君は休暇ではなくて　修行で
B-But Jinbei-kun isn't on vacation...
He's training.
The fact that he isn't here
makes him just as guilty.
ここにいない時点で同罪である
はい　申し開きもできません
I can't really disagree.
It doesn't matter...
まあよい　最初から貴様ら市中組に期待など微塵もしておらん
I never expected anything from
the City Patrol, anyway.
Huh?
Shirasagaki-dono, what are those?
白榊殿　それは
さあ　松ノ原　括目してみよう
Now, Matsunohara...
Behold!
These are...
これは
Five cannons, bought with my
massive personal fortune.
我が有する大量の金子で購った強大砲
今までよりさらに改良し　威力が増した
I've improved on the previous designs
to make them more powerful.
これさえあれば　おぬしらなぞいなくとも
Now Edo will be safe without you.
江戸は安泰よ
So he called me here
to show these off, huh?
要するに　これが自慢したくて呼ばれたわけか
た　大変です　夢久様
T-Trouble!
Yumehisa-sama...
What is it? You're quite loud.
なんだ　騒々しい
そ　それが
W-Well...
江戸が　江戸市中が
Edo... Edo is...
おお　これはおいしい　お春殿にも教えて差し上げたい
This is great...
I can't wait to tell Oharu-dono.
ああ　仁兵衛がひいきだというその団子も
Yeah, I must try these dumplings
you're always talking about.
一度食べてみなければな
Yes, Father.
はい父上　こちらの団子も素晴らしいですが
These dumplings are splendid,
「春夏秋冬」の団子の柔らかさ
but the dumplings at Shunkashutou are
so soft, bouncy, and delicious...
むっちりさ加減　張り　艶
Hey...
おい　誰か手を貸してくれ
Can someone help me?
な　なんと
Wh-What?
What happened to him?
これは一体どうなされたのですか
ここに来る途中の村が　丸ごと潰されて
All the villages I passed on my
way here were destroyed.
む　村が
Villages?
うん
He was the only one left alive,
so I brought him here.
この人だけ　まだ息があったから　連れてきたんだが
む　蟲が
I-Insects...
人の姿のような蟲たちが
Insects that looked like men...
They killed us in an instant.
あっという間に村の人たちを
村の方　その蟲はどこに
Mister, where did they go?
飛んでいった　江戸のほうだ
They flew toward Edo.
They were looking for the
Insect Magistrate's Office.
蟲奉行所を探していた
The Insect Magistrate's...
蟲奉行所を
父上
Father—
Father...
父上
怖じ気づく暇があるなら　行かぬか
If you have time to worry,
you have time to move!
Show them the new Tsukishima-style
techniques you've learned!
蟲が修行で得た月島流の神髄　とことん見せて参れ
Yes, Father!
はい　父上
I'm on my way!
月島仁兵衛　行って参ります
What is this?
なんだ　これは
Oops.
いけない　一匹だけつまむつもりが　ついつい
I just meant to eat one,
but you can't help it sometimes.
I-It talked!
しゃべった
Is it not an insect?
蟲ではないのか
It can't be.
まさか
How many did it kill on its way here?
ここに来るまでに　一体どれだけの人を
And how dare it attack our city?
そして　よくも我らの江戸を
この　蟲ケラが
You insect!
My Murakumo's bullets don't hurt it?
効かない　叢雲の銃撃が
I know you.
お前たち　知ってる
虫奉行所の者たちだな
You're with the Insect Magistrate's Office.
あの奇妙な若侍はどこだ
Where's that weird young samurai?
Young samurai?
若侍　誰のことだ
Who are you talking about?
If you don't know, that's fine.
分からないなら
消えた
It disappeared?
Shirasagaki-dono!
白榊殿
武家見回り組尾上影忠が加勢いたす
Oogami Kagetada, Samurai House Patrol, here to help!
Then I'll help, as well.
ならば私も
役立たずの市中組の手は借りん
We don't require the useless City Patrol's help!
But...
ですが
お前はそこの町民でも助けておれ
You assist the injured or something.
松ノ原　そいつを連れ
Matsunohara, take him to be treated.
急ぎ　治療に当たれ
Leave him to us!
こやつの始末は我らに任せよう
では
Very well.
Stop it from escaping!
あやつの動きを止めろ
Silkworm formation!
蚕の陣
Shirasagaki, we'll attack together.
白榊　同時に参るぞ
Understood.
よかろう
A single deadly strike!
乾坤一擲　一握の剣
Blade Hand!
優美　華麗　催馬楽の舞
Beautiful and elegant!
Saibara Dance!
効かぬか
It didn't work?
Then how about this?
ならば　これではどうだ
喰らえ　強大砲
Taste my five cannons...
これぞ寺社組の力よ
The Temple and Shrine Patrol's power!
バカな
Impossible.
我の大砲がまるで効いてない
My cannons had no effect...
まだだ　撃て撃て　撃ちまくれ
I won't give up!
Keep firing!
Interesting.
面白い　だが足りんな
But it'll take more than that...
Let's go, monster!
行くぞ　化け物め
I haven't fought nearly enough!
まだまだ暴れ足りぬわ
It's useless.
無駄だ
What a shame.
なんたる無様
I couldn't do a thing...
何も　できなかった
I will ask again.
もう一度聞く
Is that strange young samurai
with the Insect Magistrate's?
あの奇妙な若侍は蟲奉行所か
知らぬ
I don't know.
I see.
そうか
ならば　死ね
Then die.
月島
Tsukishima...
仁兵衛
Jinbei?
Honor demands you refrain from
interfering in another's battle.
無粋であるぞ
人の戦いに水を差しおって
Please tell me one thing.
一つだけ　お聞かせください
Did it do all this?
すべてはこいつの仕業なのですか
そうか
Oh!
お前か
Then you are he.
みーつけた
I found you.
Time to get rid of you!
露払いを　始める
まずい
Oh, no...
下がれ　月島
Get back, Tsukishima!
汝が太刀打ちできる相手ではないわ
You can't fight him!
こいつ　何という速さ
It's so fast...
He's keeping up with that monster.
あの化け物と渡り合っている
常住
Always be ready for a fight!
戦陣
He defeated something we couldn't touch?
我らが手も足も出なかった相手を
Koga-style Insect Ninjutsu.
甲賀流　蟲忍術
な　何と
Wh-What?
忍術
Ninjutsu?
Is that a clone technique?
まさか　分身の術か
ではどちらかが幻
Then, one of them is an illusion?
ならば今一度斬るのみです
So I just need to attack them both again.
It feels real... This is no illusion!
この手応え　これは幻ではない
Did he win?
やったか
手応え…あり
I felt the blade pierce it.
It cloned itself again?
またも分身
Who said I was cloning myself?
誰が分身だと言った
これぞ甲賀流蟲忍術奥義
This is a secret technique of
Koga-style Insect Ninjutsu,
分裂の術よ
Splitting Technique.
Each time I am killed, I maintain
my power and increase in number.
能力はそのままに　斬られれば斬られるほど増えてゆく
This splendid body makes that possible.
全てはこの素晴らしい体によって出せる技だ
我らの力の前に　貴様ら人間如きに一部の勝機もあると思うな
You humans have no hope of victory against us.
行くぞ
Go...
若侍を　殺す
Kill the young samurai!
斬れば斬るほど 増えていく
The more I kill,
the more there are.
一体　どうすれば
What should I do?
終わりだ　若侍
It's over, young samurai.
猿飛佐助　若侍の首　獲ったり
Sarutobi Sasuke has slain the young samurai!
What's wrong with you, Tsukishima?
何よ　月島
相変わらずどんくさいわね
You're always so slow.
Hibachi-dono!
火鉢殿
恋川殿
Koikawa-dono!
Tenma-dono!
天間殿
Hey, monsters.
おいおい　そこの化け物共
You've been causing damage while we were off
俺らがちょっくら修行くせぇしてる間に
随分と人のしま荒らしやがって
on our little training mission.
What? You were training?
何と　修行を
I'll slice you to ribbons, insects!
細切れにしてやんよ　クソ蟲共
紫陽花玉
Hydrangea Blossoms!
Repentance Slash.
懺斬り
全力突っ張り
Full-Power Slap!
Too easy.
ざまはねぇな
All right!
よし
So these wimps gave you trouble?
こんなやつに手こずるなんて
あんた　弱くなったんじゃないの
Have you gotten weaker?
まだです
We haven't won yet.
What is this?
ちょっ　何よこれ
斬ってはだめです
A blade's no good.
They divide with their splitting technique.
分裂の術で斬るほどに増えていくのです
斬るのがだめなら
If we can't use blades,
燃やしちゃえばいいじゃん
I'll burn them!
So annoying and gross!
うざい　キモイ
Not using blades isn't an option.
斬るなと言われてもよ
Matsukichi!
末吉
Tamekichi!
為吉
Full-Power Slap!
全力突っ張り
There are too many.
きりがねぇ
一度退散しよう
Let's fall back.
No!
だめです
この物のために　どれだけの人が犠牲になったか
Do you know how many it's killed?
If we retreat here, even more will die.
ここで我々が退いてしまっては　更に多くの犠牲者が出る
We cannot run now.
今　背中を見せるわけにはいきません
But what do we do?
そんなこと言ったって　どうすりゃいいのよ
無理だよ　こんなの
We can't fight these guys...
何かあるはずです　何か
There must be something.
Something...
Look over there.
ちょっとあそこ
死体が残ってる
One's still on the ground.
Over there, too.
あそこにも
Wh-What?
な　何と
それがどうしたんだ
Who cares?
だから
Because...
Why do some regenerate, while others don't?
どうして再生する死体と　しない死体があるのよ
You're right...
そういや
Th-Their heads!
あっ　頭
Look, those bodies have no heads!
見て　残ってる死体には頭がないよ
おいおい　ってことは
Wait, does that mean...
If we destroy the heads...
頭を潰せば
They won't split?
分裂しない
But we have to do it simultaneously.
でもやるなら　一遍にやらないと
一匹でも逃したら　どこかでまた分裂される
If we let a single one survive,
they'll go elsewhere and split again.
おいおい　これだけの数を　どうやって一遍にやっつけるってんだ
Come on...
How will we kill so many at once?
分かりました
I know how!
I have an idea.
自分に考えがあります
皆さんのお力を　貸していただけませんか
Will you help me?
Humans, how you struggle doesn't matter.
人如きがどれだけ足掻こうが　所詮は無駄
It will avail you naught!
I won't let you escape!
逃がさん
It doesn't matter what you do.
お前らが何をしようと　同じこと
You'll just make me stronger.
俺の力を増すだけだ
We're counting on you, Tsukishima.
任せたわよ　月島
Take 'em out.
頼んだぜ
Tsukishima-style:
月島流
Fuji Hammer!
富嶽鉄槌割り
You killed us all at once?
バ　バカな　一度に俺を
ちょっとはやるじゃない
Not bad.
Seems a long time since
we were all together...
何だかこうやって集まるの　久しぶりな感じするな
Even though it's only been three days.
3日くらい顔合わせなかっただけなのによ
They defeated that monster...
あの化け物を倒すとは
The City Patrol.
市中見廻り組
皆様のおかげで　見事あやかしの物を退治することができました
With your help, I managed
to defeat the monsters...
Thank you so much!
お勤めお疲れ様です
I did it, Father...
やりました　父上
I was able to use the Fuji Hammer in battle!
富嶽鉄槌割り　見事実戦でも使うことができました
小鳥殿
Kotori-dono...
The Insect-men have made it to Edo...
ついに江戸まで蟲人が…
蟲人？
Insect-men?
Kishuu Province
それにしても　今日はいい天気だ
It's nice weather today!
Time for lunch!
昼飯にすか
You're really good.
うまい
Jinbei, you must train your eyes!
Next Time
仁兵衛　目を鍛える修行だ
Follow that movement with your eyes!
あれを目で追え　上下
はい
Yes!
特訓になりますね　お春殿の胸の動きは
Watching Oharu-dono's breasts
bounce is great training.
このエロ親子が
You two are both perverts!
Next time, on Mushibugyou:
次回　蟲奉行「いざ紀州へ！真田十傑蟲、現る！」
To Kishuu.
To Kishuu!
The Ten Crucifix Insects of Sanada Appear!
The Ten Crucifix Insects of Sanada Appear.